

# Can KILIÇ

METU Software Engineer Frontend Developer

July 27, 1998

🔁 Ankara, Turkey

+905530649089

anklc9598@gmail.com

## Languages

English Turkish

Russian



### Skills

- ReactJS JavaScript TypeScript
- Redux Zustand MobX TanStack Query
- Jest Playwright
- HTML5 CSS (SASS/SCSS)
- Tailwind CSS Bootstrap
- Storybook Ant-Design
- Highcharts AGGrid
- NodeJS/Express
- Microservice Micro Frontend
- ESLint Stylelint
- Git Gitlab Github Bitbucket
- Figma, xDesign

### Links



cnkilic



can-kilicc-



cankilic

### **About Me**

After my graduation in Civil Engineering at METU, I gathered my courage to make the switch to software. I dedicated all my free time to full-stack courses. After acquiring basic knowledge about the industry, I have moved on to specialize in Front-End development using the **ReactJS library**.

Currently, I am employed as a **Front-End Developer** at Inavitas, where we bring data analysis to life through visually **appealing and user-friendly tables and graphs using ReactJS, Javascript and Typescript**. In my free time, I stay current with industry advancements by **doing side projects and learning new technologies.** 

I am eager for a challenging opportunity that allows me to utilize my skills and experience while offering opportunities for growth and advancement.

### **Experiences**

#### **Inavitas | Front-End Developer**

September 2022 - Ongoing

- Led the transformation of our React application to a micro front-end architecture, ensuring alignment with updated designs. Achieved 100% coverage of main features, decreased customer wait time by 35%, and reduced build-time by 60%.
- Covered core functionality by **unit and e2e tests**, resulting in a **30% reduction** in bug-related delays and a **20% increase** in overall code quality.
- Collaborated with industry leaders like TAB Gida, Havelsan, and TEIAŞ on diverse projects including natural SCADA, Plant, and Business. Ensured punctual delivery of new features and played an active role in resolving bugs, resulting in a 20% increase in customer satisfaction.
- Enhanced user engagement by maintaining and updating over **15 widgets** on the dashboard page, resulting in **25% boost** in overall dashboard usability.
- Worked with scrum and agile development principles using JIRA and collaborated with team members using Microsoft Teams.

#### Arina Digital | Front-End Developer

April 2022 - September 2022

- Developed the entire front-end of the Teknik Card project from scratch. This
  included developing a fully responsive website consisting 20 pages.
- Achieved a 30% increase in user engagement and a 25% decrease in bounce rate by translating Figma designs into pixel-perfect and user-friendly web and mobile interfaces.
- Contributed to the renovation and development stages of Mbis and Klimasan projects, resulting in improved project outcomes and efficiencies.

### **Certifications**

- React The Complete Guide (50 hours) || Full-Stack Web Development Bootcamp (55 hours) || Data Structures and Algorithms (20 hours) Udemy
- Using Python to Access Web Data || Python Data Structures || Getting Started with Python – Coursera

### **Education**

BC Civil engineering METU Sept 2016 - Aug 2021

• CGPA: 3.60/4.0 (5th/456)

### **Activities**

#### **Work and Travel**

June 2019 - Sept 2019 Washington DC, USA

 Learned how to communicate with people with a different language and express myself in English better.